University Information Technology Records UA161
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
University Information Technology Records
1988 -- 2019
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts Computing and Communications Services
University Information Technology
Kahle, David J.
UA161
2.25 Linear Feet 4 boxes
24 Digital Object(s) 17 of the 24 digital objects comprise 3,838 files.
23.4 Gigabytes
University Information Technology (UIT) is a university-wide service dedicated to the strategic planning, implementation and support of technical products and services for the Tufts community. This collection contains records of UIT and the Office of the Chief Information Officer, including reports, brochures, posters, presentations, communications, meeting minutes, photos and videos.
Conditions Governing Access
University records are closed for 20 years from the date of their creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trusteees records are open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA or further details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the University Information Technology Office, 2008-2020.
Appraisal
Go-Pro videos of a Tufts Technology Services bowling outing that were part of accession UA-2020-052 were not retained due to their large file size and lack of research value. Records and Accessioning Archivist, Jane Kelly, contacted the Office of the Chief Information Officer to inform them of this decision and ensure they had access to the original files if necessary.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in received order in two series: Additional accessions, and the Office of the Chief Information Officer records.
Biographical / Historical
University Information Technology (UIT) is a university-wide service dedicated to the strategic planning, implementation and support of technical products and services that anticipate and meet the academic and business needs of the Tufts community. Under the direction of the Vice President and Chief Information Officer, UIT delivers information technologies to the university that faciliate teaching, learning, research, administration and outreach.
Scope and Contents
University Information Technology (UIT) is a university-wide service dedicated to the strategic planning, implementation and support of technical products and services that anticipate and meet the academic and business needs of the Tufts community. This collection contains the records of UIT and the Office of the Chief Information Officer including reports, brochures, posters, presentations, communications, meeting minutes, photos, and videos.
Information Systems; University history
- Additional accessions, 1993 -- 2012; UA161.001; 7 Digital Object(s); 7.27 Megabytes
  - Strategic plans, budget proposals and reports; TCCS five year plan, Turn Futility into Utility pamphlet, and Strategic Plan, 1993 -- 2008; UA161-001 (Box data_value_missing_5906db2e4da96c715f3183496aa72856, Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    20 years from date of creation.
    - Strategic Plan, 2008; UA161-001.00001
  - ITC/TCCS binders and general IT policies, 1997 -- 2002; UA161-002 (Box data_value_missing_1d8ab0d5210a7c7b47f840053edb6610, Box 2)
  - Mobile Mindfulness posters and tote bag and pen/paper; Compute Safely brochures, 2012; UA161-005; 5 Digital Object(s); 3.9 Megabytes (Box data_value_missing_ea94582ad99aeec33c9e850ace6cbfdb, Box 3)
    Open for research.
    - Mobile Mindfulness posters, 2012; UA161-005.00001; 5 Digital Object(s); 3.9 Megabytes
  - Tufts Technology Services files, 1988 -- 2007; UA161-006 (Box data_value_missing_a6c91479b3ff28fe649c15b2a6e58610, Box 4)
    Scope and Contents
    Tufts Technology Services newsletters and brochures, TAB survival kit, Next Generation Directory, and Trusted Identity Management Committee records.
  - Tufts Identity Management Steering (TIMS) committee, 2003 -- 2005; UA161-007
    Identity Management Steering committee
- Office of the Chief Information Officer records, 2010 -- 2019; UA161.000011; 23.4 Gigabytes; 17 Digital Object(s) 17 digital objects comprising 3,838 files.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred by the Office of the Chief Information Officer, February 2020, accession UA-2020-052.
  This series contains records from the Office of the Chief Information Officer. These records include presentations, reports, communications, meeting minutes, photos, and videos. The material dates from 2010 to 2019, which includes David J. Kahle's tenure as Tufts' Vice President for Information Technology and Chief Information Officer from 2009 to 2018. These records document the Office of the Chief Information Officer and Tufts Technology Services (TTS) more generally, including records of committees and external partnerships, presentations and documentation about TTS for Tufts faculty and staff, photographs of TTS outings and staff events, New England Association of Schools and Colleges accreditation documents, and information on hiring and personnel.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in received order in one sub-series: David J. Kahle records.
  - David J. Kahle records, 2010 -- 2019; UA161.000028; 23.4 Gigabytes; 17 Digital Object(s) 17 digital objects comprising 3,838 files.
    - Administrative files and video footage of David Kahle, 2015 -- 2019; UA161.000012; 2.6 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 6 files.
      This folder originally contained one file about TTS. Files that were not within a folder were bundled with this single item and video footage of David Kahle.
    - Annual Report for Executive Vice President's Office, 2014 -- 2016; UA161.000013; 105.3 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 3 files.
      Annual reports for the Executive Vice President's Office.
    - Design, 2015 -- 2017; UA161.000014; 14.1 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 5 files.
      Documents related to Tufts Technology Services' design thinking and service design practices.
    - Memories of David J. Kahle, 2014 -- 2018; UA161.000015; 1.9 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 16 files.
      Photos, videos, and other material related to former Tufts Chief Information Officer David J. Kahle's memorial.
    - New England Association of Schools and Colleges accreditation, 2013 -- 2019; UA161.000016; 5.4 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 11 files.
      Tufts Technology Services reports and contributions to the NEASC Accreditation process, including documents related to the School of the Museum of Fine Arts and Tufts' NEASC 5 Year Interim Report.
    - Office of the Chief Information Officer key presentations, 2011 -- 2018; UA161.000017; 3.8 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 614 files.
      Meeting presentations and supporting documents for faculty, staff, trustees, and Tufts' executive leadership. Presentations cover information security audits, administration and finance, IT support, and town hall updates.
    - Office of the Chief Information Officer meetings, 2011 -- 2018; UA161.000018; 3.6 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 1,321 files.
      Presentations and related documents for meetings with various groups. These groups include: Administration & Planning Subcommittee, external partners and groups, CIO Council, Digital Humanities - Support Structures for Programs at Tufts, Enterprise Operations, Executive Vice President Staff Council, Faculty IT Liaison Program, IT Advisory Committee, IT Leaders Forum, Provost's Office, Support Services Steering Team, Trustees, Tufts Library Council, and University Risk and Compliance Committee.
    - Operations, 2011 -- 2018; UA161.000019; 26.6 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 28 files.
      Records of IT operations, including material related to the Federal Communications Commission, Tufts Service Desk Requests for Proposals, the School of the Museum of Fine Arts, and the Tufts network. Also includes records created by Compliance Process Partners, LLC, related to IT Service Management at Tufts.
    - Orientation materials for senior leadership, 2015; UA161.000020; 15.4 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 6 files.
      Presentations and reports about Tufts Technology Services for members of the senior leadership at Tufts.
    - ProvostOffice-Connect, 2011 -- 2017; UA161.000021; 524.3 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 59 files.
      Documents related to video conferencing and collaboration tools, including WebEx and Box.
    - Tufts Effectiveness in Administrative Management (TEAM), 2012 -- 2016; UA161.000022; 41 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 772 files.
      Meeting documents related to communications, program plans, IT resources, customer satisfaction metrics, strategic plans, IT organizational structure, organizational design and personnel, and executive committee meetings.
    - Tufts Technology Services communications, 2010 -- 2018; UA161.000023; 2.2 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 267 files.
      Staff newsletters, memos, and presentations.
    - Tufts Technology Services forums, 2015 -- 2018; UA161.000024; 4.4 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 112 files.
      Presentations and videos from monthly Tufts Technology Services Forums.
    - Tufts Technology Services photos, 2015 -- 2018; UA161.000025; 4.1 Gigabytes; 2 Digital Object(s) 2 digital objects comprising 610 files.
      Photographs from Tufts Technology Services social events, including holiday parties and summer outings.
    - Tufts Technology Services service disruption reports, 2014 -- 2016; UA161.000026; 135.9 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 4 files.
      Reports about disruptions to TTS services.
    - Tufts Distinctiom Awards - Tufts Technology Services submissions, 2014 -- 2017; UA161.000027; 518.1 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 4 files.
      Tufts Technology Services submissions to the Tufts Distinction Awards, which recognize the exceptional accomplishments of faculty and staff.